<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Orugallu</string>
    <string name="inf_txt">HEgfbgfxghfgf</string>
    <string name="inf_txxt">Warangal is a city in the south Indian state of Telangana. It was the capital of the Kakatiya dynasty from the 12th to 14th centuries, and many intricately carved monuments from this period still stand. Among them are the ruins of 13th-century Warangal Fort and the Thousand Pillar Temple, built in 1163. Set on a lake, Bhadrakali Temple dates to the 7th century and is dedicated to the Hindu goddess Kali.\
Area: 471 km²\
Metropolitan area: 1,805 km²\
Weather: 31 °C, Wind S at 11 km/h, 64% Humidity\
Population: 7.54 lakhs (2018)\
Other Names: Orugallu; Ekasila Nagaram; Tri-City\
Districts: Warangal Urban; Warangal Rural</string>
    <string name="bht_inf">The temple is believed to be built in 625 A.D by the King Pulakeshin II of Chalukya dynasty to commemorate his victory over Vengi region of Andhra Desham, as per the writings on the temple wall.

    Kakatiya kings later have adopted the temple and considered Goddess Bhadrakali as their "Kula Devatha". A lake was also built by Ganapati deva adjacent to the temple. Due to the fall of Kakatiya dynasty to the Muslim rulers of Delhi, the temple lost its prominence. The Kakatiyas negotiated a truce with Allauddin Khilji by offering the diamond in exchange not to be invaded. He sent his slave and personal confidant Malik Kufur to personally transport the diamond. In 1950, the temple was renovated by Sri Ganapathi Sastri a devi upasaka along with the help of a local merchant and other affluent locals.Apara Ekadashi is observed as Goddess Bhadrakali Ekadashi.The history of the Koh-i-Noor diamond; part of British Crown Jewels, is closely associated with this temple as it was installed, as the left eye of Goddess Bhadrakali by the Kakatiya dynasty.</string>
    <string name="kkk">
    Address: Warangal, Telangana \</string>
    <string name="rmpt_inf">Ramappa Temple also known as the Ramalingeswara temple is located 77 km from Warangal, the ancient capital of the Kakatiya dynasty,15km from Mulugu, 209 km from Hyderabad in the state of Telangana in southern India. It lies in a valley at Palampet village of Venkatapur Mandal, in erstwhile Mulug Taluq of Mulugu district, a tiny village long past its days of glory in the 13th and 14th centuries. An inscription in the temple dates it to the year 1213 CE and says it was built by a General Recherla Rudra, during the period of the Kakatiya ruler Ganapati Deva.

    The temple is a Shivalaya, where Lord Ramalingeswara is worshipped. Marco Polo, during his visit to the Kakatiya Empire, allegedly called the temple "the brightest star in the galaxy of temples".Ramappa Temple stands majestically on a 6 ft high star-shaped platform. The hall in front of the sanctum has numerous carved pillars that have been positioned to create an effect that combines light and space wonderfully. The temple is named after the sculptor Ramappa, who built it, and is perhaps the only temple in India to be named after a craftsman who built it.

    The main structure is in a reddish sandstone, but the columns round the outside have large brackets of black basalt. These are carved as mythical animals or female dancers or musicians, and are "the masterpieces of Kakatiya art, notable for their delicate carving, sensuous postures and elongated bodies and heads".

    The Temple is included in the proposed UNESCO World Heritage Site "The Glorious Kakatiya Temples and Gateways", in 2019 on the "tentative list". The proposal was submitted to UNESCO on 10 September 2010.</string>
    <string name="SSJ_inf">Sammakka Saralamma Jatara is a festival to honour the Hindu tribal goddesses, celebrated in the state of Telangana, India. This Jatara is known for witnessing one of the largest people gatherings in the world. People offer Bangaram:The Jatara begins at Medaram in Tadvai mandal in Mulug district\
                            The main jatara is held once in every 2 years.\
                            Jatara can be considered for Intangible Cultural Heritage of Humanity tag of UNESCO.\

    </string>
    <string name="tpt_inf"> Rudreswara Temple locally known as Veyisthambala Gudi (Thousand pillars temple) is one of the fine and earliest available examples of Kakatiya art, architecture and sculpture. It was built by Rudra Deva, and named after him as ‘Sri Rudreswara Swamy temple with the presiding deity as Rudreswara, in 1163 AD in the style of later Chalukyan and early Kakatiyan Architecture, star-shaped and triple shrined (Trikutalaya). The temple is a fine specimen of architecture and sculpture with One thousand pillars. There are richly carved pillars, perforated screens, exquisite icons; rock cut elephants and the monolithic dolerite Nandi as components of the temple. Strengthening of foundations like sandbox technique, the skill of Kakatiya sculptors is manifest in adroit craftsmanship and flawless ivory carving technique in their art. The ingenuity of Kakatiya sculptors is visible in likes of lathe turned, and shiny polish in dolerite and granite stone sculpture and craft work of Nava Rangamandapa.You can find a huge monolith Nandi, made up of black basalt stone.</string>

    <string name="pmt_in"> Padmakshi Gutta or Kadalalaya basadi consists of a Jain temple dedicated to Goddess Padmavati, located on a hilltop in the heart of the town of Hanamakonda, was originally constructed during Kakatiya reign.\ Till the Kakatiya Kings renovated and established the Goddess Padmakshi, previously it was a Basadi a Jain temple. In the garbhagriha, there is a massive Tirthankara Parshvanath image, with yaksha Dharanendra to the right and the goddess Padmavati (Padmakshi) to the left.[1]. The images, all carved from live rock, have been retouched and painted.Padmakshi Gutta or Kadalalaya basadi consists of a Jain temple dedicated to Goddess Padmavati, located on a hilltop in the heart of the town of Hanamakonda, was originally constructed during Kakatiya reign.\ Till the Kakatiya Kings renovated and established the Goddess Padmakshi, previously it was a Basadi a Jain temple. In the garbhagriha, there is a massive Tirthankara Parshvanath image, with yaksha Dharanendra to the right and the goddess Padmavati (Padmakshi) to the left.[1]. The images, all carved from live rock, have been retouched and painted.</string>
    <string name="timings_ramapa">Hours of visit:\
    Open on all days of the week from 5 AM – 6PM</string>
    <string name="acc">Accommodation:Haritha Lake View Resort\
                        Open on all days of the week from 5 AM – 6PM\</string>
    <string name="Laknavaram_inf">The lake was built by the rulers of the Kakatiya dynasty in 13th Century A.D. Explore the massive Laknavaram Lake, a spectacular waterbody located in the Jayshankar-Bhupalpally district of Telangana. This breath takingly beautiful lake is an amazing and popular tourist spot in Telangana. The lake is simply an exceptional thing of beauty. It is well-known for its wonderful hanging bridge, considered one-of-its-kind in the state.The Laknavaram Lake which is nestled amidst the hills was also expanded to provide a source of irrigation. The hanging bridge takes you to the mini island in the lake.</string>
    <string name="bting_inf">"Laknavaram Lake Warangal Boating Charges\
        50 per person for Adults\
        30 per person for Children\
        300 for Speed Boat (Max. 4 people) "</string>
    <string name="bgtwf_in">Bogatha is colloquially called as "the Telangana Niagara" and "Telangana Niagara Jalapatham".\
        The second largest waterfall located in the state of Telangana. This is an offbeat place which proffers mesmerizing and picturesque views of the colourful and rich landscape that circumscribes it. The variegated hills from where the water bubbles and cascades down in a tortuous manner is simply beautiful. Falling from an elevation of 30 feet, many small gushing water streams coalesce to form a large magical pool at the bottom. The water of the Bogatha Waterfall later on merges with the Godavari river. Bogatha Waterfalls is a hidden gem that will prove to be a great getaway from the hustle bustle of the city and give you an opportunity to spend some time in the lap of nature and enjoy the pleasant sound and touch of bountiful water drops.\
        Even though water flows throughout the year, a good time to visit is between June and November (after the monsoon), when the most water flows. There is no road facility, so visitors have to trek for some distance to reach the waterfall.
    </string>
    <string name="bgt_st">Near by Attractions:\
        Bogateswara Swamy Temple\
        Butterfly Garden\
        Watch Tower</string>
    <string name="pak_in">Pakhal Lake is a man-made lake in the Pakhal Wildlife Sanctuary in Warangal district, Telangana.\
        The great Kakatiya, Telugu king Ganapati Deva has constructed Pakhal lake in the deepest forest area for the future uses of farmland for agriculture purpose. Now approximately 3Lakh Acres of the area is surviving under it. Kakatiya rulers have lot of future plannings to make peoples lives better. They used so many kinds of engineering technologies in the constructions.They built Ramappa temple on a lake, as well as thousand pillars temples at Hanamkonda is constructed on sand land and still surviving for past thousand years and they will be standing so strongly other 2 to 3 thousand years so proudly after our generation.\
    The Pakhal lake which is enveloped by the scenic forested hills, is spread over an area of 30 Sq. Kms. The harness of a small tributary of the River Krishna. </string>
    <string name="pkhws">The Pakhal Wildlife Sanctuary is a striking manmade lake, which was completed in the 1213 AD by the royal Kakatiyas. This beguiling sanctuary is spread over an area of 860 square kilometers. The place gets more interesting as this amazing plateau region is surrounded by a mesmerizing range of low hills. The environment of the sanctuary and the Pakhal Lake as an add-on form the most stunning sight ever.\
        It experiences Tropical climate.The Temperature is between 15 - 45 Degrees.The Avg rainfall is 1225mm.
        The flora consists of mixed forests, bamboo and teak forests.\
        Fauna found here include Sambar(Deer), Nilgai(Blue bull), Sloth Bear, Leopard, Chowsingha (four-horned antelope), Chital, Chinkara (mountain gazelle), Wild Boar, blackbuck.\
        Commonly found reptiles are python,cobra,common krait,montior lizard,crocodiles</string>
    <string name="mdrm_nba">Nearby Attraction:\
    Jampanna vagu is a tributary to river Godavari.\
    Chilakalagutta Medaram.</string>
    <string name="bt_inf">The temple which is counted as one of the oldest temples of Indian History is dedicated to the worship the mother of goddesses, Kali Matha or Bhadrakali Ammavaru. Goddess Bhadrakali is a true example of the capability and strength of women. Surrounded by the lush greenery amidst the hilly region, the Bhadrakali Temple opens up to a picturesque setting on the banks of the Bhadrakali Lake. The serene surroundings of the temple work as an add-on and help the mind to relax and soothe the soul, while one gives away in obedience to the supreme power.</string>
    <string name="bt_tim">Hours of visit:\
                          All Days of the Week\
                          5:30 AM - 1:00 PM\
                          3:00 PM - 8:30 PM</string>
    <string name="tptt_inf">"The Thousand Pillar temple has three presiding deities, Lord Vishnu, Shiva and Surya Deva. The temple stands as a statement of the finest of arts of the Kakatiyas. "</string>
    <string name="timing">Hours of visit:\
                          All Days of the Week\
                          5:00 AM - 9:00 PM</string>
    <string name="wfrt_inf">It was the capital city of Kakatiyas and Musunuri Kamma Nayakas. It appears to have existed since at least the 12th century when it was the capital of the Kakatiya dynasty. The fort has four ornamental gates, known as Kakatiya Kala Thoranam, that originally formed the entrances to a now ruined great Shiva temple.</string>
    <string name="wfrt_innn">Near by Attractions:\
        The Kush Mahal\
        \
        
        Hours of visit:\
        All days of the week\
        10:00 am – 7:00 pm</string>
    <string name="etuws_inf">Eturnagaram Wildlife Sanctuary is a wildlife sanctuary located in Eturnagaram village in Mulugu district in Telangana.The sanctuary is located near the Maharashtra, Chhattisgarh and Telangana border. It is one of the oldest sanctuaries of Telangana. In the year 1952 on 30 January the erstwhile Hyderabad Government because of its rich bio-diversity declared it as a sanctuary.Godavari river passes through the sanctuary. The vegetation here is tropical dry deciduous with teak and other trees of good quality standing 60 ft (18 m) and above.\
        \

        The biennial festival of Sammakka Saralamma (Medaram) Jatara is held in the sanctuary.\
        \

    On the top of it, the wildlife sanctuary area has some historical significance owing to the existence of tree fossils in this Sarvai area and caves.\
        The sanctuary has southern tropical dry deciduous type of teak and its associates like thiruman, maddi, and bamboo, madhuca, terminalia, pterocarpus.\
        A perennial water source called "Dayyam Vagu", divides the sanctuary into almost two halves. It is home to Tiger, Leopard, Wolf, Dholes, Golden jackals, Sloth bear, Chousingha, Blackbuck, Nilgai, Sambar, Spotted deer, Chinkara, Indian giant squirrels and many kinds of birds. Reptiles like Mugger crocodile, Python, Cobra, Krait, Star.\
        \
        Best time to visit : October to May\
        \

Accommodation : Forest Cottages and Rest House Tadvai, ITDA Guest House at Eturnagaram.\
        \
        Attractions:\
        Forest Trekking\

Bird Watching\

Forest Cycling\

Kondeti View Point\

Night Camping\

Nature Trail\


</string>
    <string name="vavnav_inf">Warangal District Administration has constructed the zoo to protect and preserve the sanctity of nature. It was opened for public in 1985. The zoo serves as both the educational and entertainment center.
The Central Zoo Authority of India has ordered to convert the zoo into a national zoological park in 2010.\
        The zoo is located on a 50-acre area, and contains a variety of species of birds, animals and reptiles.\
        \
        
        Hours of visit:\
        9:30 am to 5:30 pm.\
Park remains closed on all Mondays.
    </string>
    <string name="invu_inf">Inavolu Mallikarjuna Swamy Temple situated at Inavolu village of Vardhannapet Mandal Warangal District and Telangana State is one of the ancient Lord Shiva temples in South India.\
        \

    The temple dates back to 11th century and was built by Kakatiya rulers. It was built with 108 pillars and has a giant magnificent Nruthaya Mandapam on eastern side. Historical Kakatiya Keerti Toranams (Giant Rocky Entrance Gates) were initially constructed here and subsequently at Warangal fort.

The presiding deity Shiva lingam of the temple referred to as ‘Ardhapranavattam’ (Shivalinga with half doom). The temple has four entrance gates with rich architectural carvings that epitomizing the cultural sophistication of Kakatiya dynasty.

The temple was built by a minister Ayyanna Deva of Kakatiya Kingdom – hence the name Inavolu. The presiding deity Sri Mallikarjuna Swamy is considered as one of the incarnations of Lord Siva. Mostly the Yadavas patronise the temples built for the deity.\
    \
    The famous Inavolu Mallanna Jatara has begun on a grand note here on Bhogi. The religious event of historic Inavolu Mallikarjuna Swamy Jatara begins on Bhogi, the preceding day of Sankranti festival and continues till Ugadi the Telugu New Year. Grand Celebrations of Makara Sankranti - Maha Shiva Rathri - Ugadi - Deepavali - Every Masa Shivarathri.</string>
    <string name="pdmsk_inf">Padmakshi Temple is one of the oldest temples in Hanamakonda City, with Goddess Padmakshi (Padmakshamma) as the main deity built by Kakatiya Kings in 12th century.Padmakshi Gutta or Kadalalaya basadi consists of a Jain temple dedicated to Goddess Padmavati, located on a hilltop in the heart of the town of Hanamakonda, was originally constructed during Kakatiya reign. Till the Kakatiya Kings renovated and established the Goddess Padmakshi, previously it was a ‘Basadi’ a Jain temple. In the garbhagriha, there is a massive Tirthankara Parshvanath image, with yaksha Dharanendra to the right and the goddess Padmavati (Padmakshi) to the left.. The images, all carved from live rock, have been retouched and painted.The temple also has rich sculpture of the Jain Tirthankaras and other Jain Gods and Goddesses. The Kadalalaya basadi or Padmakshi Temple is built on a large rocky out crop.\
    \
    The exceptional feature of the temple is the impressive four faces of a pillar called the Annakonda pillar, which is a quadrangular column made of black granite stone, is at the entrance of the temple.</string>
    <string name="raya_inf">Hours of visit:\
        Monday - Friday: 6:00 AM -6:00 PM\
        Saturday: 6:00 AM -6:00 PM\
        Sunday: 6:00 AM -6:00 PM\
        Public Holidays: 6:00 AM -6:00 PM</string>
    <string name="bpwfss">Bheemuni Paadam Waterfalls is the one of the best tourist places to visit in Warangal district. There is a rock in the form of Bheemas foot print, through which the water flows thus it is named as Bheemuni Paadam (Bheemas foot print). When sun rises and sets the water shines in rainbow colors which is an amazing sight. The water drops down from a height of about 70 ft to form a fool at the bottom. The flow of water is heavy in monsoon season. A cave beside the falls which is believed to be 10 km long is the other attraction here.  The approach road to the falls runs through thick forest and water streams. The waterfall is about 3 kms from Bhupathipet between Manoharabad and Narsmapet. While coming from Warangal, take left turn at Bhupathipet and reach the falls via Chinnayellapur.\
        Apart from the waterfall, there are several lakes nearby which can be visited as well. There are idols of Lord Shiva and Nagadevatha in a small enclosure near the falls where visitor perform poojas.\
        \
        
        Best time to visit the waterfalls is during monsoons.</string>
    <string name="swaya_inf">"The Sri Swayambhu Temple is one of the most important pieces of architecture found in the Warangal Fort of Telangana. It is important not only in terms of its historical value but also owing to the insight it provides on the craftsmanship of Kakatiyan sculptors.  Built under the Kakatiyan dynasty the temple is dedicated to Lord Shiva. The Shiva Linga which still exists is of special significance as it is believed to have emerged out of the earth on its own. Hence it has been named the Swayambhu Shambu Lingeshwara Swamy temple. Swayambhu literally means to be self-incarnated. The Sri Swayambhu Temple Warangal is 846 years old and was once regarded as the most important place of worship for the Kakatiya kings. Its history retells its days of glory when the great Kakatiya king Prataprudra visited the temple regularly to offer his prayers to Lord Shiva. This vital fact renders its small size, which might otherwise have led it to be ignored by tourists, as insignificant.\
        \
         The pillars and arches that are available display intricate carvings of figures. Each carving is unique in their attention to detail that is obvious in the intricacies that have been displayed. It is also interesting to note that though stone, the carvings have beautifully captured delicate details like the jewelry designs of dancers, the facial expressions of the deities or the physical strength of the animals displayed on the motifs. Moreover, the sheer size of the ceilings and brackets leaves tourists amazed and awestruck.

The walls and ceilings of the temple also depict the Perini dancers. Though the temple carvings display female dancers, the Perini dance form however was essentially performed by soldiers prior to leaving for war. In fact, it was the carvings like these which inspired Acharya Nataraj Ramakrishna to revive the Perini dance form.\
        \
        In addition to these several mythical characters like the Makara Dwajas adorn the structures assumed to have been ceilings. The craftsmanship depicted in these carvings indicates the superior quality that architecture had achieved in the medieval era. Moreover, if individual pieces could evoke such emotions, it is awe-inspiring to imagine what the temple would have looked like in its entirety. Every visitor is left envisioning this through the mind’s eye.

The temple premises housed around 23 Shivalingas or shrines. Most of these were plundered and the precious gems embedded in them were extracted. The ruins remind tourists of the plunder and vandalism that these marvels had been subjected to."</string>
    <string name="ktagu_inf">"Ghanpur temples, popularly known as Kota Gullu, are a group of 12th century stone temples that are located in Ghanpur near Warangal\
        Kota Gullu were constructed by King Ganapatideva.\
        \
        Kota Gullu comprises about 20 temples, all varying in size and design that exhibits the marvelous architectural work by Kakatiyas.

Temples are constructed within a double walled stone enclosure. Of all these temples, the main temple, dedicated to Lord Shiva, is the most admirable. There is yet another temple that is dedicated to Shiva, to the north of the main temple, that looks alike in appearance. The other shrine of the temple consists of Garbhagriha and Antarala.

The most striking feature of the temples is the Sabha mandapa porches. Two madanikas are seen on the northern side of the portico. The eastern and southern porticos are embellished with several mythical figures of Gaja Kesari, half human-half lion form riding on elephant, and horse-head lion back on elephant."</string>
    <string name="muse_inf">The District Archaeological Museum of Warangal is located behind the Warangal Municipal Corporation Office  in the city. The Museum was established in the year 1991.  Warangal being the capital of erstwhile Kakatiya Kingdom is an archaeologist’s delight and there are many articles in the museum belonging to Kakatiya dynasty which impresses visitors with their grand display. The museum has Contemporary Paintings, Coins, Bronzes, Arms and Weapons, sculptures and Inscriptions belonging to Western Chalukyas and Kakatiyas on display.  The District Archaeological Museum, Warangal also hosts a wide range of archaeological artifacts such as pre historic antiquities, palm leaf manuscripts, sculptures, arms and weapons. In addition to the sculptures, fossils, early historic antiquities, stuccos, Bidriware, coins, terracotta, chinaware, and enamelware are also displayed here. The museum showcases paintings, miniature paintings and sculptures. The display gallery boasts of epigraphs, copper plates, grants and bronzes. Historians and book lovers find the library of the museum very much resourceful as it well stocked and well maintained.\
    \
   Hours of visit:\
    10:30am AM to 5:00pm PM\
closed on Fridays and Public Holidays</string>
    <string name="regina"><![CDATA[Regional Science Centre, Warangal is the focal point of TSCOST for various Science Communication / Popularization processes. Regional Science Centre, Warangal portrays state-of-the-art features on the best science communication mechanisms with a view to develop curiosity and inquisitiveness towards science and technology in the minds of students, teachers, academicians and general public.\
    \
    Edu-Sat facility : Vigyan Prasar, Dept. of Science & Technology, Govt. of India, New Delhi installed one Satellite Interactive Terminal (SIT) of Edu-SAT, at RSC, Warangal, which provides two-way audio-visual interaction of scientists, academicians, and subject experts with students, academicians, and a wide range of target groups on various topics of science and technology. Several theme based programs on rural development, energy conservation, environment and biodiversity protection, science popularization shall be organized periodically.]]></string>
    <string name="hema">Nestled in the thick forest near to the Godavari river at Mallur village in Mangapet mandal, the Hemachala Lakshmi Narasimha Swamy temple is alluring hundreds and thousands of pilgrims from different parts of the State and the neighbouring States.

Located 1,500 feet above the sea level on Puttakonda (hillock), Lord Narasimha is believed to be incarnated from a volcano and his body is felt and sensed same as that of a human body — even with ‘hair’. If you press your fore-finger on the chest of the idol, you can see the finger literally sinking into the rock without resistance. Once you take out the finger, you can watch the trough formed due to the pressing slowly filling up leaving an impression on the chest.
According to the priests, the temple has a history of 4,776 years and it was Agastya, the great sage, who named the hillock as Hemachalam.

Temple chief priest K Raghavacharyulu says, “You cannot see an idol of this kind in any temple in India. The 9.2 feet tall idol of the deity oozes out some liquid like water from navel which is served to the devotees. It is a divine wonder to note that the sandal in the fluid form flows through the umbilicus (navel) of the great Maha Vishnu. Chintamani jalapatham and koneru near the temple have its water originated at lord’s feet.”  He also adds that it was Rani Rudrama Devi who named the stream (small jalapatham) after Chintamani.

Devotees are seen either taking a bath or taking the water in the bottles and tins from the stream at the hillock.

Water from the hillock as it has many medicinal values.</string>
    <string name="panda_inf">Attractins:\
    Rock Climbing\
        Rappelling\
         Hiking\
        \
   Hours of visit:\
        08:00 am to 06:00 pm\
        All days open\
        \

        Ticket Price:\
        Children = RS: 10/-\
Adult = RS: 20/-</string>
    <string name="temples">Temples</string>
    <string name="agutta_inf">On the Aggalaiah Gutta, right opposite the Padmakshi gutta in Hanamkonda, a 35-foot tall carving of 3rd Thirthankar of Jainism, Sambhavanatha in the Kayotsarga pose, can be seen atop a huge boulder.  Just a few steps away, a 13-foot tall carving of the 23rd thirthankar, Parshvanatha, can be seen. A carving of the seven thirthankars can be found on another boulder below this one.  Each of the 24 Jain Tirthankars has a symbol which distinguishes them. In the big carving, a horse can be seen near the feet. This confirms it is Sambhavanatha. Also, there is a snake in the other carving which confirms it is Parshvanatha. The carving of Sambhavanatha is found nowhere else in South India, says historian and epigraphist Katta Srinivas.  In between these two thirthankars, a carving of Jain Basadi is seen which reveals that followers of Jainism meditated on this hillock. Further, after the Parshvanatha carving, hidden by some trees are 55 steep steps leading to the top that were carved in the same fashion as Shravanabelagola. But an interesting factor about these steps is that five are carved with tirthankar symbols — tortoise, elephant, Boar and other animals have been carved into this space. There is also open area on the top with two walls which belong to the Kakatiya period.\
        \
        Srira-moju Haragopal said the statue is of the 24th Tirthankara of Jainism, Mahavir.  According to Mr Haragopal, the presence of the Jain carvings and caves suggests that the place was once a ‘Jaina aramam’ or a place of meditation. “It can be concluded from the carvings seen on the statue that it is indeed Mahavir. However, more research is required to know more about the statue. The statue has evidently lost its original colour over the years. A ‘Thristhala chakram’ explain can be seen above the head of the statue. The symbol of Mahavir, that a lion, can be found below. Among the Jain statues found across Telangana, those of Shanthinatha, Prashv-anatha, Mahavira and Rishabhanatha are found in more numbers,” he said.</string>
    <string name="metuguta_inf">"The Kakatiya Kings who ruled this city had built many architecturally and sculpturally beautiful buildings and temples.  Kakatiya kings being Shivaites have built many Shiva temples.\
        \
        On the way to the temple.  The one seen is Ganesha temple. The piled stones - Twin rocks are called as 'Donthulamma gundlu' These were stones with which Hidimba played 'kacchakayalu'.\
        \
        Mettugutta Ramalingeshware temple is special for its serene location on hillock surrounded by rocks, trees and water trenches.    The rocky road to the temple passes between rocks and trees and water trenches. According to local people, in this beautiful place love blossomed in the hearts of Hidimba and Bheemasena.  The area between the twin rocks was the abode of Hidimba and people believe that Bheemasena had fallen in love with Hidimba during their exile into forest.  Another mythological story is attached to this place.  Lord Rama during his forest stay along with Sita had lived in this area.  Here, he worshipped Lord Shiva – Swayambhu Linga.  As Shri Rama worshipped, Lord Shiva here is called as Ramalingeshwara.  Temple is said to be built by Kakatiya kings.  Lord Rama’s temple also is built here.\
        \
        There are nine gundams (water trench) – Pala, Ginne, Kannu, Kathi, Rama pada/ Bheema, Brahma, Vara, Mangala, Chakali gundams, around these temples.  These gundams will never dry up in any seasons.\
        \
        The temples will be open everyday in the morning from 6AM to 1PM and 5PM to 7PM for regular rituals.  On second Sunday of every month 'Mahanyasa Poorvaka Rudraabhishekam’ is performed by the Mettu Ramalingeshwara Seva Samithi.  All the material for this ceremony is provided by the Seva Samithi and anybody can participate in it for free. Those who want to take part in the abhishekam should reach the temple before 8AM, men should wear lungi and shella on shoulders and women should wear sarees.  After the abhishkem lunch is served for all. Special festive rituals are held on Mahashivaraathri and Sree Ramanavami, when people throng for puja and abhishekam. "</string>
    <string name="swethaganapati_inf">"SWETHARKAMOOLA Ganapathy is also known as ‘Sankalpa Siddhi Karakudu’, SWETHARKAMOOLA Ganapathy possess all organs of Ganesha. They are nither carved nor moulded by any sculptor. They are naturally formed and his form is amazing with clear eyes, forehead, teeth, wisdom tooth, legs, feet, hands, navel, bed and throne and we see him sitting on a rat on Mooshika Vahana, his mode of transport.\
        \
        Swayambhu Sri Swetharka Ganapathi temple is situated in Vishnupuri Colony, Kazipet of Warangal District.  Thousands of devotees throng in long queues for the darshan of Lord SWETHARKAMOOLA Ganapathy. This has been a continuous process for last 14 years. Lord Ganesha has been fulfilling the desires of tens of thousands of devotees whoever solemnly walks around the temple chanting his name with mere grass (Garika, Agrastis Linearis) on hand. People believe that it is at mere sankalpa (thought or desire) in the temple, their solemn desires would be fulfilled by his grace and also get assurance of being accomplished.\
        \
        Swamy is exactly seated facing east side and it appreas as if God is looking at North-East (Eshanya) extending his eyesight to Kailasa, the Heaven of Siva. This is an indication that Lord Ganesha is a dissipater of all Vaastudoshas too. This is one of the unique features of Lord Ganesha. Further a Purana story narrates that the present posture of Ganapathy is the result of a war that occurred between a Mooshika (rat) and an Asura. It was during the war Lord Ganesha seems to have pulled out his right tooth and broken it and thrown the half broken tooth at the enemy. Then the enemy seems to have come to the rescue of Lord Ganesha and touched his feet to protect him. It is after the end of war, Lord Ganesha seems to have seated comfortably and quietly in the present position and this is being considered as another unusual feature of Lord Ganesha. "</string>
    <string name="tt_inf">The Telangana State Tourism Development Corporation is a state government agency which promotes tourism in Telangana.\
    \
    For any kind of tour packages to Divine places, Wildlife sanctuaries and many more.Telangana tourism is at service with attractive packages.\
    \
    For any other details click the link below.</string>
    <string name="hotel_info">To reserve your room click the link below.\
        \
        https://www.oyorooms.com/5078-capital-o-capital-o-3420-hotel-ashoka-warangal/</string>
    <string name="citygrand">To reserve your room click the link below.\
        \
        https://www.oyorooms.com/61174-capital-o-capital-o-42989-moksha-city-grand-warangal/</string>
    <string name="suprabha">To reserve your room click the link below.\
        \
        https://www.oyorooms.com/1500-capital-o-capital-o-1251-hotel-suprabha-warangal/</string>
    <string name="harita_inf">To reserve your room click the link below.\
        \
        https://telanganatourism.gov.in/partials/stay/warangal-urban/haritha-kakatiya-hotel.html\
    \
    https://harithakakatiya.com/</string>
    <string name="mark_inf">To reserve your room click the link below.\
        \
        https://www.oyorooms.com/91297-capital-o-capital-o-66968-haveli-the-landmark-warangal/</string>
    <string name="ratna">To reserve your room click the link below.\
        \
        https://www.goibibo.com/hotels/bratna-hotel-in-warangal-8861585155419369428/</string>
    <string name="shreya">To reserve your room click the link below.\
        \
        https://www.goibibo.com/hotels/shreya-hotel-in-warangal-1681506220832276616/</string>
    <string name="raghava">To reserve your room click the link below.\
        \
        https://www.oyorooms.com/94471-oyo-rooms-oyo-68943-raghavendra-residency-warangal/</string>
    <string name="crysta">To reserve your room click the link below.\
        \
        https://www.oyorooms.com/27318-oyo-rooms-oyo-12973-hotel-crystal-warangal/</string>
    <string name="shreshta">To reserve your room click the link below.\
        \
        https://www.oyorooms.com/55454-oyo-rooms-oyo-37003-hotel-shreshta-inn-warangal/</string>
    <string name="radika">To reserve your room click the link below.\
        \
        https://www.oyorooms.com/40660-premium-oyo-17316-radika-residency-warangal/</string>
    <string name="satya">To reserve your room click the link below.\
        \
        https://www.oyorooms.com/35889-oyo-rooms-oyo-13775-sathya-lodge-warangal/</string>
    <string name="mitra">To reserve your room click the link below.\
        \
        https://www.oyorooms.com/18896-oyo-rooms-oyo-11938-mitra-residency-warangal/</string>
    <string name="grand">To reserve your room click the link below.\
        \
        https://www.goibibo.com/hotels/bgrand-gayathri-hotel-in-warangal-5826541604640094144/</string>
    <string name="ekashia">Ekasila Park is a public park located in Hanamakonda, Warangal, India. Beuatiful nature surrounded this park. Very enjoyble atmospher for children.\
    \
    Address: near Warangal Fort, Mathwada, Warangal, Telangana 506002</string>
    <string name="sme_inf">Special Attractions of this is temple with Lord Shiva and Lord Vishnu sanctum in adjacent caves.\
    \
     It is dedicated to the Deity Someshwara and dates back to the Chola period. The temple has a history of 1,200 years.\
    \
    </string>
    <string name="sme">There is an alight hillock at a height of 120 meters, The Someshwara lakshmi Narashima temple is a unique in its structure and the location.The legends Lord Shiva and Lord Vishnu are the two powerful gods of the Hindu Trinity, there are two caves formed next to the hillock. The someshwara Lakshmi Narasima temple is formed in the caves. The hills around the temple form a natural road for the devotees to circle the shrine. This road around the temple is used to do pradakshina by the devotees. It is available almost in all temples. The temple someshwara Lakshmi Narasima is dedicated to the Lord Shiva and Vishnu.We can observe a well uniqueness of the temple. When we enter into the inner chamber we can see two dwarapalikas which seems to be shiva in Nataraj Posture. In Nataraj Posture we can see damaru holding in one hand and the structure are made with black stone. At the entrance of the Shiva temple we can see Nandi bull graces at the entrance. The both sides of the walls have great specimens of the architecture and look amazing. We can see a different atmosphere near the narrow caves. During the festival season it is too difficult to control the devotees because they used to come for darshanam in a huge numbers. There is a famous telugu poet palakuriki somanathudu, named the village as palakurthi. It is a famous seat of veerashaivisim. This is the faith of 6000 years old primarily in the southern states of Telangana and Karnataka and the western state of Maharashtra. Irrespective of class and caste this has a progress in teaching and it also stood against those barriers.On the life of Basava, the Basava puranam is written by the Palakuirki. He is the great teacher of the Veerashaivism faith in the poetry form.This helped to popularize poetry among people and raised the standards of Somnathudu’s place of birth. Palakurthi presently came to be revered as Palakuriki’s birthplace and was consequently named once him. Palakurthi so attracts massive devotees of the Veerashaiva sect United Nations agency need to be blessed every by the spirit of the nice author however as by the presiding deities of the Sri Someshwara deity Narsimha Swamy Temple.The temple assumes nice focus throughout the Omaha knife Ratri competition. Typically this can be} often a Hindu competition that\'s accepted with plenty of magnificence and gaiety. Every year on the thirteenth or ordinal day of the month of Hindu calendar month (mid-February among the Gregorian calendar) devotee’s are seen thronging the temple premises with Bael (stone apple or wood apple) leaves and flowers to produce prayers to Lord Shiva. The place comes alive with chants of ‘Om Namah Shivaya’ the principal component of the Panchakshara mantra. Devotees are seen acting penances to realize boons and blessings from the lord.</string>
    <string name="kush">"Khush Mahal is said to be built during Tughlak reign in 14th century.\
        \
        It is also considered to be built on the old palatial complex of Kakatiya reign. Traces of Tughlak architectural style is still seen on this structure. For instance, the walls of the Mahal which are slightly inclined are indicative of the structural style of that period. However, according to some it was built by Shitab Khan, the then Warangal Governor of Qutub Shahi Dynasty. He then used Khush Mahal as an auditorium. Hence, it is also known by the name of Shitab Khan Mahal.\
        \
        It is an audience hall with a huge chamber that is facing north. The chamber has arch shaped opening on all the four sides. Earlier, this hall has a timber roof which is not seen now. One can see style of Delhi contemporary architecture in this structure, consisting of massive walls and northern orientation.  Khush Mahal has sloping walls and slanting arches which are specific characteristics of structure built during Tughluq dynasty. Longer walls of the mahal, on the eastern and western side, have projecting stockade and six arches with thin rectangles through which light enters the hall. The main chamber is spacious with high ceilings. It can be entered through a huge entrance on the north. There are small storage rooms on each side of the hall.  There is also staircase attached to the hall. One can reach the top of the building through a staircase and admire the captivating view of Warangal Fort and surrounding areas. Near the north entrance, idols that were excavated from the nearby areas are displayed. One can see broken remains of Jain Temple and Svayambhu enclosure inside the Khush Mahal. "</string>


</resources>
